超能力者警报
大伙  我看到警报了  超能力者袭击市中心
Guys, I saw the alert. Meta attack downtown.
-我现在赶过去  -好的  闪电侠
- I'm on my way. - Sounds good, Flash.
卡米拉  是你吗
Kamilla? Is that you?
-是我  -还有切斯特·P·朗克  长官
- Uh, yeah. - And Chester P. Runk, sir!
准备协助你的一切超级英雄需求
Ready to assist you in all your superhero needs.
为什么是你俩负责通讯
Why are you two on comms?
-卡米拉让我进来的  -这里只有我们俩
- Uh, Kamilla let me in. - We're the only ones here.
冰霜去天眼会看血怒了
Frost is at A.R.G.U.S., checking on Bloodwork.
西斯科去整理危机之后的
Cisco's off the grid,
超能力者名单  不见了踪迹
cataloging post-Crisis metas.
爱瑞丝去调查新闻了
Iris is on a story--
拉尔夫追查苏·迪尔邦
And Ralph is who-knows-where,
也不知道追到哪里去了
tracing down Sue Dearbon.
好吧  不必担心  我自己搞定
Okay, no worries. I'll do this solo.
你确定不需要帮助吗
Are you sure you don't want some help?
因为我已经准备好了  非常乐意帮助
'Cause, I mean, I'm--I'm ready, willing,
而且精力充沛  长官  算上我吧  老大
and caffeinated, sir. Put me in, coach!
谢谢  切斯特  不过我能搞定
Thanks, Chester, but I'm good.
哈特利·拉瑟威
Hartley Rathaway.
你什么时候变成钻石大盗了
Since when are you a diamond thief?
叫我吹笛人  闪电侠
It's Pied Piper, Flash.
而且在你和你朋友对我做出那些事后
And you're really gonna ask me that
你还好意思问我这个问题吗
after what you and your friends did to me?
我们做了什么
Uh, what did we do?
我的天  闪电侠
Wow, Flash.
老兄  你还真是非一般地冷酷
My brother, that is epically cold.
你怎么能记不得了  他之前相当惨
How do you not remember? It was really bad.
好极了  又一个危机造成的变化
Oh, great. Another Crisis change.
很明显  还有件事你不记得了
Apparently, there's something else you don't remember.
护腕只是我的备用发声器
The gauntlets are just my backup singers.
什么情况
Wait, what?
这下可好
Great.
-他现在还会飞了  -不用担心  闪电侠
- He can fly now. - No worries, Flash.
P·朗克在全力搜查
P-Runk is all over it.
音爆有特定的频率
That sonic boom had a specific frequency.
如果我能扫描与之相同的波长
If I scan for the same wavelength,
系统  声波来源
正在扫描频率
我想我们就能...
I think we can...
目标所在地
52街和棕榈街交汇
找到了
Voilà!
闪电侠  拉瑟威在52街和棕榈街交汇
Flash, Rathaway's at 52nd and Palm.
好的  我这就从百老汇路过去
All right, I'm on it. I'll take Broadway.
-我不建议你那么做  长官  -为什么
- Uh, I wouldn't do that, sir. - Why not?
因为有一辆...
Because there's a...
这里什么时候有了火车的
Since when was there a train here?
一直都有
Since always.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第十三集
系统更新完成
System update complete.
还有什么需要的吗  巴里·艾伦
Is there anything else, Barry Allen?
还有一处需要调整
Uh, just one more tweak.
与此同时  我想在我再去出外勤之前
In--in the meantime, I wouldn't mind knowing everything
知道危机所造成的所有变化
that Crisis changed before I run back into the field.
计算中...
Calculating...
巴里·艾伦是闪电侠
Barry Allen is The Flash.
-是的  我早知道了  -什么
- Yeah, I already knew that. - What?
实际上  仔细想想
A-actually, you know what? When I think about it,
这也确实合理  整个尖端科研实验室的
it does kinda make sense. The whole S.T.A.R. Labs
超级设备  还有  每次闪电侠来精神增强室
super-facility... Plus, the same voice
看我的时候  声音也和你一样
every time The Flash came to visit me at the M.A.C.
还有你的下颌线  非常独特
And that jawline, though? Very distinctive.
抱歉  伙计们
Listen, guys, I'm sorry.
我有点  我现在有点忙
I'm kinda-- I'm kinda busy right now.
你在忙什么
Well, what are you working on?
-我...  -分析完成  巴里·艾伦
- I... - Analysis complete, Barry Allen.
我计算出大约有3.725万亿种变化
I've calculated approximately 3.725 trillion changes.
你是否要按照因果关系来听一下
Would you like to hear them in order of causality?
这是移动交互式人工智能装置吗
Is this a mobile interactive artificial intelligence unit?
是的
Yeah, it-- it is.
我只是想给它升级
I'm-- I'm just trying to upgrade it.
真的吗
Really?
如果你把电子螺线管转过来
You know, if you just flip the positronic solenoid--
别动  请...
Hey, you know, please,
不要乱动  这些东西很敏感
You don't mess with that. It's, it's sensitive stuff,
而且你也不是我们的队员  切斯特
and, you know, you're not on the team, Chester.
当然
Yeah, totally.
看来我要把超级英雄技术支持这项工作
I guess I'll cross the whole superhero tech support
从我的可选职业中删除
off my list of career possibilities.
那我先失陪了
Anyways, if you'll excuse-moi...
我是吉特咖啡店的粉丝
I'm Jitters-bound.
-他只是想帮忙  -我知道
- He's just trying to help. - I know.
我知道  只是...
I know. It's--
危机之后
So much has changed...
改变太大了
after Crisis, and...
今早  我收到超能力者警报的时候
You know, this morning, when I got the meta alert,
我在试着找我父母的墓
I was trying to find my parents' graves.
但是那个地方已经不是墓地了
There's not even a cemetery there anymore.
我找遍了中城所有的墓地
I-- I searched every graveyard in Central City.
还是找不到
I still can't find them.
感觉失去了一部分灵魂
Just feel like a piece of me is missing.
还有像哈特利·拉瑟威那样的朋友
And friends like Hartley Rathaway
现在变成了敌人
are enemies now.
一切都那么不同了
Just-- everything is so different.
通讯器里传出不同的声音也没帮上什么忙吧
I'll bet hearing different voices on comms doesn't help, either.
你想要熟悉的事物  我们不是
You want something familiar. That's not us.
我不是这个意思
Hey, I didn't mean it like that.
没事  巴里  我明白
It's okay, Barry. I understand.
也许你可以对切斯特好一点
Just maybe take it easy on Chester.
如果他看起来有点过于热切
If he seems a little overeager,
是因为他把闪电侠当做偶像
it's because he idolizes The Flash.
你是他的英雄
You're his hero.
你继续忙你的吧
I'll... let you get back to it.
这肯定有某种逻辑性可寻
There's gotta be some sort of logic to it.
再和我说说
Walk me through the night
粒子加速器爆炸那晚的事
of the particle accelerator explosion again.
你当时在做什么
What were you doing?
我和你说过了
Like I told you...
那晚我开始在做反射芯片扩张调制器测试
I was starting R-CEM tests that night.
我刚做好原型  我一生的心血已经完成了
I just finished the prototype. My life's work was ready.
反射芯片扩张调制器原型
等等  你的机器造好了吗
Wait, you finished building your machine?
-是的  -你能在这里再造一个吗
- Yeah. - Can you build one here?
可以  但我们不能用
I did, but we can't use it.
伊娃  我们至少得试试
Eva, we at least have to try.
你为什么这么害怕
What are you so afraid of?
我
I...
伊娃  我明白  真的
Eva, I get it. I do.
但是我看过你的研究
But I've read your research.
你非常杰出
You were brilliant.
你在你的领域中是最优秀的
You were the best in your field.
这对我来说我就够了
And that is good enough for me.
你这么勇敢
You're so brave.
那我们就一起勇敢吧
I guess we'll be brave together, then.
这就是残余粒子捕捉器
So this is a residual particle catcher.
它可以侦测和捕捉物体的分子余辉
It can detect and detain molecular afterglow of things.
好的
Okay.
那你需要我做什么
And you need me to do what?
我要你帮我充电  这样我就能抓住他
I need you to help me charge this so I can catch him.
它们  那些粒子
Them. Particles.
-捕捉那些粒子  -你为什么这么紧张
- Catch the particles. - Why are you so nervous,
你要捕捉的这些粒子是什么
and what are these "Particles" you're trying to catch?
没什么  它们只是...
Noth-- they're just-- they're--
它们是科学异常
They're scientific anomalies.
你不理解的
You wouldn't understand. -
这就是我们都认识的恼人的纳什·威尔斯
There's the Nash Wells we know and can barely stand.
我猜异常是因为危机的原因吧
And I'm guessing anomalies because of Crisis?
女老板告诉我了
Boss Lady told me. -
是啊  你从来不喜欢被隐瞒  对吗
Yeah, you never did like being kept in the dark, did you?
你为什么总是表现的像是认识我很久
Why do you always act like you've known me forever?
太奇怪了
It's weird.
我
I...
不知道你在说什么
Don't know what you're talking about.
这可不是实话  对不对
Well, that's not true, is it?
你可真是个骗子
You're such a liar.
什么  我是说
What? I mean...
这个  是
It's, uh--yes.
残余粒子捕捉器准备好了  谢谢
The residual particle catcher is ready, thank you.
如果你可以的话  请你
So if you would, please,
你能不能  帮我  充一下电
can you, um, help me, uh, charge it?
就用你那
Just blast it with
超能量紫外线打这里
a ultra-powered UV ray right there.
-哪里  -那里  就...
- Wh-where? - There, right--
瞄准那个...
Just aim for the...
吸收面板
The absorption panel
-就在前边  谢谢你  -好  别太激动了
- on the front pylon, thank you. - Okay, keep your panties on.
那装置可不会起作用
That contraption is not going to work.
你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
她是谁
Who the hell is she?
她  那是
She-That's--
那个  就是我以前认识的一个人
That's--it's just someone I used to know.
她看起来很像是我的二重身
Well, she looks a lot like my doppelganger.
你为什么有她的照片
Why do you have a picture of her?
这不...  这不重要
It doesn't ma-it doesn't matter.
对我来说重要
It does to me!
老兄  这太奇怪了  你知道  我有感觉
Dude, this is too weird. You know, I had a feeling
从一开始我就觉得你不对劲
something was off with you from the beginning,
但是我一直在无视它  因为我只是高兴
but I kept ignoring it, because I was just happy
找到一个能信任我的人
to find another person who actually believed in me.
-好吧  -但这么久以来
- Okay. - But this whole time,
当你看着我的时候  你看到的是另一个人
when you looked at me, you saw this other person.
天啊  这真是糟透了  知道吗
God, that is messed up, you know?
好吧  好
Okay, all right.
我们再试一次  吉迪恩
Let's try this again, Gideon.
怎么回事
What the hell?
-很好  你醒了  -凯特琳
- Oh, good, you're awake. - Oh, Caitlin.
感谢上帝  这是怎么回事
Thank God. What the-w-what the hell is going on?
我是说  前一分钟
I mean, one minute,
我在极速实验室  修复吉迪恩
I'm in the speed lab, fixing Gideon,
接下来我就到了这里
and the next thing I know, I'm here.
我的速度消失了
My speed's gone.
今天你的话还真多啊
Quite the little chatterbox today, aren't we?
什么
What?
你为什么这样跟我说话
W-why are you talking to me like that?
还有我为什么在笼子里
And why am I in a cage?
凯特琳  放我出去
Caitlin, let me out of here!
放松  杀手
Easy, killer.
斯旺
Thawne?
你还真是个人物啊
You're quite the specimen, aren't you?
下地狱去吧
Go to hell.
我不知道你是怎么把我拉来过去的
I don't know how you managed to drag me back to the past.
不管这是什么  我都会阻止你
Whatever all this is, will stop you.
脾气真大
Cranky.
怎么  你跟他提B打头那个词了吗
What, did you offer him the B-word?
也许他只是需要点隐私
Maybe he just needs some privacy.
我去看下罗尼  他在设计个新地方
I'm gonna go check on Ronnie. He's working on a new space
他可有干劲了  他叫那里管道监狱
he's very excited about. He's calling it the Pipeline.
管道监狱
Hmm. The Pipeline.
我喜欢这名字  凯特琳
I like the sound of that. Caitlin.
-我跟你一起去  -凯特琳
- I'll come with you. - Caitlin.
凯特琳  不要相信他
Caitlin, do not trust him!
中城警局
宝贝女儿
Hey, baby girl.
是什么风把你吹来了
To what do I owe the pleasure of this visit?
希望是一条好线索
Well, a good lead, hopefully.
我在写关于黑洞组织的文章
I'm working on our Black Hole story,
但是我现在陷入了严重的瓶颈
and I have reached a major dead end,
我在想你们有没有新的关于
and I was hoping that maybe you found something new
约瑟夫·卡弗的线索能帮到我
on Joseph Carver that could help.
事实上  还真有新线索
Ah, as a matter of fact, I have,
但是我不能跟你分享
but I can't share it with you.
-你是认真的吗  -是这样的
- Are you being serious? - Uh, well, look.
卡弗的这个案子现在已经成为
This Carver case has become
一个反腐调查案  我必须直接上报给
a RICO investigation. I have to report directly
辛格局长  我们需要按章办事
to Chief Singh. We have to do everything by the book.
巴里告诉我
Barry told me that
是你建议他相信我去使用镜像枪
you were the one that gave him the advice to trust me
然而你现在这件事上面
with the Mirror Gun, and now you can't even trust me
-又不相信我  -爱瑞丝  那个武器
- with this? - Oh, Iris, that weapon
是属于闪电侠小组的领域  这是中城警局的事
was Team Flash territory. This Is CCPD business,
而且也要保持这样  不然  卡弗可以
and it has to stay that way. Otherwise, Carver could skate
-起诉我们暗中勾结  -爸  卡弗是我的
- with a collusion charge. - Dad, Carver is mine.
你不能就这么把我挤掉
You can't just shut me out.
我不是  我不是这个意思  我
I didn't--I didn't mean that. I, um...
这个案子  对我意义很大
This just--it-- it means a lot to me.
我看出来了
I can see that.
但是宝贝女儿  我束手无策啊
But baby girl, there is nothing I can do.
我无能为力  抱歉
My hands are tied. I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry too.
我们两个都有各自的工作要做
We both have a job to do,
我尊重你
and I respect that.
我  我正要去吃午饭
I, um--I'm about to get some lunch.
你想不想和我一起去大贝利汉堡店吃点
Do you maybe wanna join me for some Big Belly Burger?
-我请客  -这个我想法我喜欢
- My treat. - Now that I would love.
但是我还有点事情要忙完  好吗
But I got a few things to finish, okay?
不要紧  你要不要正午的时候店里见
Yeah, no worries. You wanna meet me there at noon?
完全可以  店里见
That's perfect. See you there.
-好  -好的
- Okay. - All right.
来吧  就玩一局
Oh, come on, come on. Just--just one game.
我刚用了两个小时的时间
I just spent the last two hours
在天眼会和拉姆齐讲话
at A.R.G.U.S., talking to Ramsey.
我不想和你玩三维弹球
I do not wanna play pinball.
再说了  我知道你留在这里的唯一原因
Besides, I know the only reason you're hanging around
是你想和巴里解决你们的问题
is 'cause you wanna work things out with Barry,
-所以快去解决吧  -什么  我
- so just go do it. - What--I'm--
我还在鼓起勇气去找他  只是
I'm working my way up to it. It's just, you know,
直到今天  我做过最坏的事是
up until today, the worst thing I'd ever done before
把我祖母的车淹了
is drown my grandmother's car.
在你11岁的时候不要尝试去造悬浮车
Uh, don't try to build a hovercraft at age 11.
行不通的
It doesn't work out.
你在难道没在中城上方
Didn't you create a literal black hole
造出来一个黑洞吗
over Central City?
你觉得巴里还在因为那件事生气吗
Oh, you think Barry's still mad about that too?
你能不能少说两句
Would you stop?
不  那发生的时候我根本没醒
No, no, I wasn't even awake when that happened.
你又没杀了他
I mean, it's not like you killed him.
巴里
Barry!
Barry?
你不说话我也没法帮你
I can't help you if you won't talk to me.
-你用手势啊  -你在干什么
- Use your signs. - What are you doing?
还没反应吗
Nothing?
每个人都有心情好坏的时候
Well, everybody's got good days and bad days.
大猩猩也是一样的
Gorillas are no different.
这不是在过去
This isn't the past.
这是脑海景象  我在
It's a mindscape. I'm in...
没错  巴里·艾伦
That's right, Barry Allen.
你现在在古鲁德的大脑中
You're in Grodd's mind now.
怎么了  古鲁德  在天眼会寂寞了吗
What's the matter, Grodd? Got lonely at A.R.G.U.S.,
所以你决定越狱来见我
so you decided to break out, come visit me?
古鲁德还在牢里
Grodd is still in his prison
是你和你的小队让他陷入的昏迷
in the mental coma you and your team put him in.
所以呢  笼子是报复吗
So, what, the cage is payback?
-所以你要复仇  -不是复仇
- What, you want vengeance? - Not vengeance.
是理解   古鲁德想要巴里·艾伦看看
Understanding. Grodd wants Barry Allen
一无所有是什么样子
to see what it's like to have nothing.
没有力量  没有自由  只有囚禁
No powers, no freedom. Only captivity.
凯特琳用神经抑制剂
Caitlin used a neural inhibitor
关闭了古鲁德的大脑
to shut down Grodd's cerebrum.
凯特琳背叛了古鲁德
Caitlin betrayed Grodd.
但你给了她权威  这是你的所为  闪电侠
But you gave her the authority. This is your doing, Flash.
我马上还会这么做
I'd do it again in a heartbeat.
你的头脑就是武器
Your mind is a weapon.
你从一个人手中夺走了武器
You take a weapon from a man,
他仍是人
he's still a man.
你夺走了古鲁德的头脑
You took Grodd's mind,
古鲁德最伟大的天赋  这不是惩罚
Grodd's greatest gift. That is not punishment.
这是残暴  赤裸裸的残暴
That is cruelty, pure cruelty.
不  从我的角度来看不是
No, no. Not from where I'm standing.
你伟大的大脑还记得
Does that great mind of yours
你伤害了多少人吗
remember how many people you've hurt?
你的猩猩大军踏遍中城
You marched an army of gorillas through Central City.
你迫使我和索罗瓦进行决斗
You forced me into a gladiator arena with Solovar.
你把鲨鱼王的心电感应王冠武器化
You weaponized King Shark's telepathic crown
从而掌控成千上万无辜的人们
so you could control thousands of innocent people.
承认吧  古鲁德  你罪有应得
Face it, Grodd. You got what you deserved.
你说的不错
You are right.
古鲁德花了一年才重新找到
It took Grodd a year to find the strength
智慧思考的能力
to think intelligently again,
在那段时间  古鲁德有很多原始的想法
and in that time, Grodd had many...primitive thoughts.
没有高等思想的力量
And without the power of higher thinking,
古鲁德再也不能骗自己
Grodd could no longer lie to himself
被迫面对自己的行径
and was forced to confront the truth of his actions,
错误和犯罪的真相
his wrongdoings, his crimes.
你的意外让古鲁德能进入你的大脑
Your accident allowed Grodd to enter your mind,
不会伤害闪电侠   而是请他帮助
not to harm Flash, but to ask for Flash's help.
神经抑制剂
The neural inhibitor
在古鲁德脑中放入了一个看门人
put a gatekeeper in Grodd's mind.
看门人所守卫的那个出口
The portal that gatekeeper guards
是这个监狱的唯一通道
is the only way out of this prison.
帮帮古鲁德
Help Grodd.
古鲁德很抱歉
Grodd is sorry.
古鲁德已经变了
Grodd has changed.
超智慧猩猩是这么说的
Says the super-intelligent gorilla
而且绑架了我
who just kidnapped me.
都不肯露脸
Who won't even show his face.
古鲁德想让闪电侠相信他
Grodd wants Flash to trust him.
你的超能力回来了
Your powers are returned.
拜托了  闪电侠
Please, Flash.
帮助古鲁德战胜看门人吧
Help Grodd defeat the gatekeeper.
想得美  古鲁德
Nice try, Grodd.
但你永远不会变
But you'll never change.
你就该待在原地
You're exactly where you belong.
真是个疯狂的卡布奇诺制造者
That's one crazy cappuccino maker.
快了
Close.
歇洛克的机器是
Sherloque's machine was developed
把一个人的思想
to put one person's mind
放入另个人的脑子里
into another person's memories.
等下  你们觉得巴里在其他人的脑子中
Wait, you think Barry's in someone else's mind?
我们之前也遇到过这种情况
I mean, we've had experience with this before.
根据巴里的脉搏  他眼球的快速移动
Based on Barry's pulse, his rapid eye movement,
还有其他生命特征
and his vitals...
而且两个脑波明显暴露了
And the two brainwaves are a dead giveaway.
这真是太棒了
This is so awesome.
太棒了  太棒了
Awesome. Awesome.
不  我是说  这很糟糕
I mean, no, this is just awful.
我们得想办法解决这件事
We should, uh-- we should fix that.
没错
Yeah.
既然拉姆齐决定去巴里的脑子里度假
When Ramsey decided to take a little vacation inside Barry's brain,
我和西斯科决定研究记忆机器
Cisco and I decided to work on the Memory Machine
以防血怒重新出现
just in case Bloodwork decided to resurface.
它们是怎么运作的
How's all this work?
在脑海景象中  本体将神经信号
In a mindscape, the host transmits neural signals
传送到客体的初级运动皮层
to the guest's primary motor cortex.
如果我们能与这种神经递质同步
If we can sync up with those neural transmitters,
就能与巴里取得联系
I think we can communicate with Barry.
就像直接给他大脑发送私信
Like sliding into his mind DM's.
厉害
Sweet.
-加油  巴里  -冰霜
- Come on, Barry. - Frost.
跟我出来一下  快来
You and me, outside. Let's go.
哈里森·威尔斯还活着
Harrison Wells is alive?
-说来话长了  -好吧
- That's a really long story. - Okay.
-有话快说  否则失陪了  -听着
- Make it fast, or I'm out. - Ah, now, look.
事实证明  阿莱格拉在经历了一些
So it turns out that Allegra, through a-- you know,
不幸的事之后  她发现
series of unfortunate events, she has discovered...
她是你女儿的二重身
That's she's your daughter's doppelganger?
并不算是我女儿  更像是雇员
Not my daughter, exactly. More like an employee, right?
前雇员  你是怎么知道的
An ex-employee-- How do you know that?
随便你怎么想  我猜结果不太好
Whatever. I'm guessing it didn't go well
因为是她自己发现的  而不是由你告诉她
because she found out rather than you explaining it to her.
现在该用老办法了  去说出实情
So now it's time for some good old-fashioned honesty.
-拜托  -不论你和你女儿之间
- Oh, come on. - Whatever happened between
-发生了什么  -她不是我女儿
- you and your daughter-- - It's not my daughter, exactly.
更像是雇员  一个做出错误决定的前雇员
Okay, more like an employee, an ex-employee who made a bad call.
对她解释清楚
Just explain it to her.
但是她说一切都太晚了
Yeah, but she said it was too late for that.
正如我的人生导师拉尔夫说的那样
Well, as my life coach, Ralph, would say,
你不能让这阻挡你
you can't let that stop you.
拉尔夫是你的人生导师
Ralph is your life coach?
终于找到了
Finally, there it is.
该离开这里了
Time to get out of here.
索罗瓦
Solovar?
你是看门人吗
You're the gatekeeper?
我们不必争斗
We do not have to fight.
据我所知
As far as I'm concerned,
古鲁德会永远处于昏迷状态
Grodd can stay in this coma forever.
我是这里的监狱长  闪电侠
I am the warden of this prison, Flash.
没有人可以逃走  你也不能
None shall escape. Not even you.
好吧
Oh, great.
巴里的身体正在对脑海景象发生的事做出反应
Barry's body is reacting to whatever's happening in the mindscape.
如果他在那里死掉  在现实中也会死吗
So if he dies in there, he dies out here too?
没错
Correct.
有镇定剂吗
Do you have any sedatives?
镇定剂对极速者不起作用
No, those don't work on speedsters.
不  我是说给自己用
No, no, no, no. I meant-- I meant for me.
冰霜  你现在的表情就和西斯科一样
Uh, Frost, you've got that look Cisco has
他接着会对我们说出一堆专业术语
before he throws a bunch of science words at us
大意就是我们完蛋了
that basically means "we're frakked."
在巴里大脑皮层中活动的信号
The signals traveling to Barry's cortex
正在以超神经高速移动
are moving at a hyper-neural speed.
我们只见过一个
We've only seen one other brain
神经元可以达到这种速度的大脑
whose neurons can fire this fast.
大猩猩古鲁德
巴里在古鲁德的大脑里
Barry's in Grodd's mind.
大猩猩古鲁德
Gorilla Grodd?
天啊  他是我最喜欢的超级反派
Damn. Yo, he is, like, my favorite supervillain ever!
他超级强壮  超级聪明
He's, like, super strong, is super smart,
巴里正被困在他的脑子里
and... Barry's super trapped in his mind,
这真是糟透了
which is very, very bad.
我们修改了古鲁德的心电感应王冠
We modified Grodd's telepathic crown
让他在天眼会继续保持昏迷状态
to keep him in a coma at A.R.G.U.S.
但它的神经抑制功能
But its neural-inhibiting capabilities
只能维持一个意识  很快
can only sustain one mind. Before long,
这个意识就会过载并崩溃
the mindscape will overload and crumble.
如果它崩溃时巴里还在里面
If that happens and Barry's still inside...
他就会死  我们不能直接打电话给天眼会
He would die. Well, can't we just call A.R.G.U.S.
让他们把它关掉吗
and ask them to shut it off?
不行  如果关掉时
Uh, no. If we do that
巴里还跟古鲁德的意识连接在一起
while Barry's still connected to Grodd's mind,
他就会永远被困在那里
he'll be trapped in there forever.
我还是不明白为什么会这样
I--I still don't understand how this happened.
古鲁德怎么会进入巴里的意识
How did Grodd get inside Barry's mind?
因为我
Because of me.
我之前调试过这东西
When I tweaked this earlier,
我把它的下丘脑连接
I adjusted its hypothalamic connection...
调到了原来的9倍
by a factor of 900%.
好吧
Okay.
这个信号强度已经足够
Well, that's more than enough signal
搭载另一个大脑了
for another brain to piggyback on.
巴里被击倒时就戴着这东西
And Barry was wearing that when he was whammied.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我根本就不该到这儿来
I--I never should've came here.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
你跑了还怎么帮我们
How's you running away gonna help us
把巴里从古鲁德的意识里弄出来
get Barry out of Grodd's mind?
因为如果我不在这里
Because if I'm not around,
至少不会把事情变得更糟
at least I can't make things worse.
听着  我真不想告诉你
Look, I hate to break it to you,
但偶尔让巴里有生命危险
but accidentally putting Barry's life in danger
基本上算是这里的一种惯例了
is kind of a rite of passage around here.
我们都干过这种事  西斯科  我  拉尔夫
We've all done it: Cisco, me, Ralph,
连清洁工都干过
even the janitor.
他在地板上打了太多蜡
He put too much wax on the floor.
但每次我们让他有生命危险之后
But then, after we put his life in danger,
我们都会想办法把他解救出来
we figure out a plan to get him out of it.
所以现在轮到你了
So now it's your turn.
我六年级的时候
You know, in the sixth grade, I got into the science fair
用吸尘器零件做成的"千年隼号"
with a "Millennium Falcon" that I built
参加过一次科技展
out of used vacuum parts.
它之前飞起来过
I mean, it--it flew
还有很多功能  像无人机一样
and everything, like a drone.
但是科技展那天
But on the day of the fair,
它没飞起来
it didn't fly.
进气管里面的铁锈阻碍了空气
Uh, rust in the intake manifold was preventing air from getting
进入燃烧室  然后导致它...
into the combustion, which was then causing it to...
对不起  总之
Sorry. Anyway,
我求我的老师让我把它修好
I had begged my teacher to let me fix it
第二天再飞一次
and then fly again the next day.
他拒绝了
He said no.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
他是老派人
He was an old school brother.
他说
And he said...
在现实世界中  我们这样的人
that in the real world, people like us...
我们没有第二次机会
we don't get a second chance.
等等
Hold on.
我不会假装了解
I'm not gonna pretend like I have any idea
你的生活是什么样的
what your life has been like,
而且我知道我们在这里做的某些事情
and I know that some of the stuff we do in here
跟现实世界没有任何关系
has nothing to do with the real world,
但我要给你第二次机会
but I'm offering you a second chance.
因为你应该拥有第二次机会
Because you deserve one.
因为我们都应该拥有第二次机会
'Cause we all do.
爸爸  对不起  我不知怎么记错了
Dad, I'm so sorry. I don't know how I made that mistake.
我记得跟你约的12点半
I--I thought I said 12:30.
没问题  我会点你平常点的菜
Not a problem. I'll order you the usual.
听起来不错  我马上过去
Yeah, that sounds great. I'll be there soon.
爱你
Love you.
约瑟夫·卡弗文档下载中
下载完成
准备好了吗  好了
Ready to do this? Yes.
不  我不知道
No. I don't know.
伊娃  看着我
Eva, look at me.
相信自己  你能做到
Trust yourself. You can do this.
我不相信的是这个机器
It's the machine I don't trust.
它发射出的亚原子粒子
The subatomic particles this emits
会穿透镜子的表面
will penetrate the mirror's surface,
但它不会突破世界之间的障碍  会失败的
but it won't pierce the barrier between the worlds. It will fail.
那我们也不会比现在更糟
Then we're no worse off than we are right now.
我能控制镜子碎片
I made the mirror pieces move.
我们再回去试试
Let's just go back to trying that.
伊娃  我们应该尽我们所能
Eva, we should be trying everything we can
离开这里  对吗
to get out of here, right?
我
I...
还有另一个你不想让我
There's another reason why you don't want me
使用这个机器的原因  是吗
to use this machine, isn't there?
没有  我  我  我  我  我最好去躺着
No, I--I--I... I--I better go lie down.
-伊娃  你在隐瞒什么  -什么都没有
- Eva, w-what are you hiding? - Nothing!
我为什么不信你呢
Why don't I believe you?
-相信我  我们不能用它  -为什么不能用它
- Trust me, we can't use it. - Why can't we use it?
因为这个
Because of this!
-我的  -伊娃
- Oh, my-- - Eva!
你现在成乔了
You're Joe now?
当闪电侠看到古鲁德
Oh. When Flash sees Grodd,
他从他的过去看到了敌人
he sees an enemy from his past.
古鲁德想让闪电侠看见一张他信任的脸
Grodd wants Flash to see a face he can trust.
让我对抗索罗瓦
And having me fight Solovar
是为了让我相信你
was supposed to make me trust you?
古鲁德认为闪电侠可以打败他
Grodd thought Flash could beat him.
你错了  他差点杀了我
You were wrong! He almost killed me!
但那就是你的计划  对吗
But that was your plan, wasn't it?
不是
No.
那是什么  发生了什么
What's that? What's happening?
那是索罗瓦吗
Is that Solovar?
这个世界正在崩塌
This world is crumbling.
神经抑制剂再也不能承受两个人的压力了
The neural inhibitor can no longer take the strain of two minds.
如果它失败了这个脑子会发生什么
What happens to this mindscape if it fails?
古鲁德和闪电侠会一起死
Both Grodd and Flash die together.
你这么想要复仇以至于为了置我于死地
You wanted revenge so badly that you were willing to die
-连自己的性命也能不要  -不是
- just to take me with you? - No.
古鲁德变了
Grodd has changed.
没有什么能让你改变
Nothing could ever make you change.
甚至是无限世界的危机也不能吗
Not even the Crisis of Infinite Worlds?
你怎么知道危机的
How do you know about Crisis?
古鲁德的大脑没有被
Grodd's mind wasn't affected
多元宇宙的融合所影响
by the merging of the multiverse,
但是古鲁德仍然能感知到现实的变化
but Grodd can still sense changes in the reality,
像猩猩城的变化  城现在在这
changes like Gorilla City. City is here now.
猩猩们现在在这  古鲁德知道
The gorillas are here now. Grodd knows this.
-古鲁德想回家  -为什么
- Grodd wants to return home. - Why?
所以你能组建另一支军队来攻击中城
So you can create another army to attack Central City
只想毁掉你路上的每一个人
just to destroy everyone in your path?
这就是古鲁德以前的样子
That is who Grodd used to be.
古鲁德想要权利
That Grodd wanted power.
权利带来不了快乐
Power didn't bring happiness.
它会带来痛苦
It brought pain.
新的古鲁德向往一条新的道路
New Grodd wants a new path.
古鲁德想要和他自己的种族
Grodd wants to live...
在平静中生存
in peace with his own kind.
猩猩城是唯一一个古鲁德
Gorilla City is the only place Grodd ever...
感到快乐的地方
ever felt happy.
你在说事实
You're telling the truth.
你真地变了
You really have changed.
闪电侠以前不相信古鲁德
Flash didn't believe Grodd before,
但为什么闪电侠现在相信古鲁德了
but why does Flash believe Grodd now?
你不再沉湎于过去
You let go of the past.
也许我也应该如此
Maybe I should do the same.
那场危机改变了很多
Crisis has changed so much.
我一直沉迷于
I've been obsessed with
试图让所有事都保持原样
trying to keep things the way they were before,
但我做不到
but I can't.
那些事都无所谓了
Those things don't matter.
如果闪电侠打不过索罗瓦  那我们绝对跑不掉
If Flash can't beat Solovar, there's no escape.
这个世界崩塌了  我们都会死
This world collapses. We both die.
这就是我们的宿命
That's our fate.
不  我们的宿命由我们自己决定
No. We decide our fate.
古鲁德  索罗瓦能够打败我是因为我还在用
Grodd, Solovar beat me because I tried to fight him
三年前一模一样的方法去和他战斗
the exact same way I fought him three years ago.
如果想要离开这里  我们必须试试新的方法
To get out of here, we just have to try something new.
我们必须勇往直前  不能后退
We have to run forward, not backward.
怎么勇往直前
How?
肩并肩一起战斗
By fighting together.
这就是我们的出路
There's our way out.
你准备好了吗  我们能做到的  古鲁德
You ready? We can do this, Grodd.
一起战斗  古鲁德已经准备好了
- Together. - Grodd is ready.
-什么情况  -巴里和古鲁德
- What is it? - Barry and Grodd.
他们的脑活动开始同步了
Their cerebral activity is syncing.
好吧  不是什么"同步"
Okay, forget "synced."
他们的神经通路刚刚合并了
Their neural pathways just merged.
他们的脑电波已经一样了
Their brainwaves are literally the same.
-感觉怎么样  -感觉难以想象
- How does it feel? - It feels impossible.
我知道  现在做好准备
I know. Now get ready.
这一次  我们是同一队的
This time, we're on the same team.
古鲁德永远都走不了
Grodd will never leave!
你已经拥有我的力量了  古鲁德
You have my powers, Grodd,
还有如何使用它们的方法
and my knowledge of how to use them.
-快把我们弄出去  -古鲁德明白
- Now get us out of here. - Grodd understands.
神经通路联结运作起来了
The neural comm link is working.
-巴里  你能听到吗  -冰霜
- Barry, can you hear me? - Frost?
太好了  我们一直在努力和你取得联系
Oh, yes! We've been trying to get in contact with you.
你在古鲁德的脑中
You're in Grodd's mind.
-他想要伤害你吗  -不  没有
- Is he trying to hurt you? - No, no.
我们在同一条船上  我和古鲁德合并了大脑
We're on the same team. Grodd and I merged our minds.
有点像烈焰风暴矩阵的
Sort of like the mindscape version
脑内版本
of the Firestorm matrix.
等等  所以你现在是半猩猩了
Wait, so you're half-gorilla now?
我稍后再解释  我们正在反抗在古鲁德脑内的
Uh, I'll explain later. We're fighting a gatekeeper
一个看门人  我们必须打败它才能逃出来
in Grodd's mind. We need to beat it to escape,
-而想要打败它...  -就只能并肩作战
- and the only way to do that... - Is by working together.
时间已经不多了
There isn't much time.
世界就要分崩离析了
The world is gonna split apart.
古鲁德觉得闪电能救他
Grodd thinks lightning can save him?
什么都救不了古鲁德
Nothing can save Grodd.
巴里  我们现在遇上比索罗瓦更大的麻烦了
Uh, Barry, we've got bigger problems than Solovar right now.
-我知道  古鲁德的脑世界要崩塌了  -这个更糟
- I know, Grodd's mindscape is falling apart. - Actually, this is worse.
还有什么能比这个更糟糕
What can be worse than this?
根据我的扫描结果  如果你逃出了他的脑子
According to my scans, if you exit the mindscape
但你们的脑电波仍然在合并中
with your brainwaves still merged,
那你们会共存于一副躯体中
you'll end up in one body.
毛绒版闪电侠  恶心  抱歉【求校
Brundle-Flash. Gross. Yeah.
而且更糟的是
And what's worse is,
这样所产生的生理冲突会导致
the resulting physiological conflict
所有的大脑细胞都停止运作
will cause every brain cell to shut down,
-所以最后的结果将是...  -我们都会死
- and the resulting form would... - We'd both die.
是的  等等  也就是说
Yeah. Wait, so we have to somehow
我们必须在他们逃出的同时分离开他们的大脑
separate their minds at the exact moment they escape?
而且我必须精确到毫秒
And I'd have to be accurate to the millisecond.
-这是不可能的  -对我们来说不可能
- Which isn't possible. - Not for us.
但是对于一个
But it's very possible
便携交互人工智能单元是有可能的
for a mobile interactive artificial intelligence unit.
如果我们把吉迪恩的量子智能网络与
If we sync Gideon's quantum intelligence network
巴里和格鲁德的生物分析系统同步
to Barry and Grodd's bio-analytics,
就可以进行完美的神经分离
it'll perfectly time the neural de-splicing.
但是我还要对这个装置做一些调整
But I'd have to do some more augmenting to this puppy,
因为我的调整害的巴里变成这样
and my augmenting is what got Barry into this mess,
我不想再出什么差错
and I--I just really don't wanna mess up again, so--
切斯特  听我说  你之前对吉迪恩的改动
Chester, listen to me. That tweak you made
在两秒钟之内
to Gideon earlier? In two seconds,
就增强了她的能力  我在两小时内都做不到
you improved her functionality more than I did in two hours.
你是个天才  或许结果和你的计划
You're a genius. Maybe it didn't work out
不太一样  你还有再试一次的机会
exactly how you planned, so here's round two.
再试一次
Try again.
我需要你  切斯特
I need you now, Chester. Please.
你可以的  我相信你
You can do this. I believe in you.
-闪电侠相信我  -我们都相信你
- Flash believes in me. - We all do.
来吧  再试一次
Go ahead, take your second chance.
让大家看看你的本领
Show us your moves.
好
Right.
垃圾场的勒布朗·詹姆斯
It's time for the LeBron James of the Junkyard
要出手了
to do his thing, baby!
兄弟姐妹们  看好了
Oh, watch out, brothers and sisters,
切斯科·P·朗克回来了
because Chester P. Runk is b-b-b-back!
很好  我们现在只需要
Great. Now all we have to--
闪电侠
Flash?
格鲁德
Grodd!
你无路可逃
There is no escape.
索罗瓦要赢了  加把劲  巴里
Solovar's winning. Come on, Barry.
-怎么样了  切斯特  -一定要成功
- How's it going, Chester? - Please let this work.
格鲁德害怕了
Grodd stinks of fear.
格鲁德知道索罗瓦会杀死他
Grodd knows Solovar brings him death.
别听他的  格鲁德  你不能死  你还有许多牵挂
Don't listen to him, Grodd. You have too much to live for.
听到了吗  别输给你的过去
You hear me? Don't let the past win.
放下你的过去  让索罗瓦看看你的本事
Put it all behind you and show Solovar what you're made of.
就是这样  站起来
That's it. Now get the hell up
快跑  格鲁德  快跑
and run, Grodd. Run!
就差一点
Almost there.
不管你们有什么手段  现在就用出来
Whatever you guys are doing, do it now.
好了
Here goes!
好
Yes!
加油  巴里  你可以的
Come on, Barry. You got this.
感谢拉奥
Oh, thank Rao.
-你回来了  -我回来了
- You're back. - Yeah, I'm back.
是队伍的功劳
Thanks to the team.
你觉得格鲁德已经成了英雄了吗
So do you think Grodd has gone, like, full hero?
还是他更像寒冷队长
Or is this more of like a-- like a Captain Cold
"曾经是坏人  现在比较像个好人"
"former villain turned sort of good guy" situation?
以后就知道了  莱拉让天眼会
Uh, we'll see, I guess. Lyla had A.R.G.U.S. embed
在他的小脑中安装了追踪聚合物
a tracking polymer in his cerebellum.
她同意让格鲁德假释出来
She agreed to let him out on probation
只要我们随时能知道他的位置
as long as we know where he is at all times.
如果他再一次变坏了  我会找到他的
So if he does break bad again, um, I'll find him.
说到这个  我要联系莱拉
Which reminds me, I'm gonna check in with Lyla
弄明白天眼会的规章制度
and make sure I understand A.R.G.U.S.' protocols.
我要确保他们真的给了格鲁德一次机会
I wanna make sure they give Grodd a real chance.
宝贝  开玩笑吗
Hey, babe. You're kidding.
太好了  什么时候
That's great! When?
西斯科要回家了
Cisco's coming home!
我有话要说
I wanted to say, uh,
我的态度不好  我很抱歉
I'm sorry I wasn't more welcoming.
我还在应付家里的事
It's--I mean, I was dealing with this family thing.
我感觉生活中的一切都变了
I felt like everything in my life was changing,
我把气撒在你身上
and I took that out on you,
对不起
and I'm sorry.
没事  闪电侠
Ah, it's-- it's all good, Flash.
顺便说一下
Um, by the way,
卡米拉跟我说了你父母的事
Kamilla told me about your parents,
我大概
and I kind of...
入侵了记载方圆七百英里范围内
hacked every cemetery database
墓地的所有数据库
within a 700-mile radius.
找到了他们
Found them.
市中心  法院
我不记得
I don't remem...
谢谢  切斯特
Thank you, Chester.
你能负责通讯吗
Do you mind manning the comms?
我还以为你永远不会说这话
I thought you'd never ask.
我们的卫星数据显示
According to our satellites,
警报  目标位置
哈特利·拉瑟威
是拉瑟威
it is... Rathaway.
吹笛人回来了  宝贝
Pied Piper's back, baby!
好吧  我需要一切可能获得的帮助
Okay, I'm gonna need all the help
才能捉住他  你准备好了吗
I can get to take him down. Are you ready?
当然
Oh, hell, yeah.
好的
All right.
真是永远不会手生
Oh, that's never gonna get old.
伊娃  我很抱歉
Eva, I'm so sorry.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me
那个机器会伤到你
that the machine could hurt you?
我想证明自己没有说谎
I wanted to prove I wasn't lying.
语言是苍白无力的
Words are worthless.
证据是无可辩驳的
Evidence-- evidence is irrefutable.
同事们都嘲笑我的反射论
My colleagues ridiculed my reflective theory.
虽然我的研究非常前沿
Even though my research was bleeding edge,
但是没有科学杂志愿意发表
no scientific journal would publish it,
因为我还没证明这是真理
because I hadn't shown it to be true.
我只是
I just...
我不能让你那样怀疑我
I couldn't have you doubt me like that.
我只是
I just...
我只是需要你相信我
I just needed you to believe me.
伊娃  我当然相信你
Eva, of course I believe you.
我看见过你移动那些镜子碎片
I saw you move those mirror pieces.
你的能力很强
You're capable of great things.
你身体恢复后  我们会
Look, when you're feeling better, we will...
我们会再想办法的
We'll find another way.
好的
Yeah.
我想我还有些绷带
I think I have some more, uh, bandages
放在储藏室里
in the storage room.
-你能去拿一下吗  -好的  当然
- Would you get them? - Yeah, of course.
你对我们做了什么
What did you do to us?
我为彼此争取了时间
I bought us time.
你不必受苦
There's no need for you to suffer.
闪电侠
【求校】
好了  放轻松
All right. Easy-peasy.
他要
He...is...
来了
Coming...